A journalist interviews an economist.
Czy rząd obniży podatki?
Trudno to jednoznacznie przewidzieć. Wydaje się jednak, że raczej nie w tym roku.
Notice how carefully he avoids a definite answer.
Pociąg najprawdopodobniej się spóźni.
Careful speakers rarely state things absolutely.
Impersonal phrases and adverbs grade how certain you are.
It cannot be ruled out that prices will rise.
Nie można wykluczyć, że ceny wzrosną.
Did you say it? Say it once more, out loud.
The train will most probably be late.
Pociąg najprawdopodobniej się spóźni.
Did you say it? Say it once more, out loud.
Now practise with the exercises below the video.